# **Rohan Ghosh**

Modinagar, Uttar Pradesh, India



+91 9690014359



Rohanghosh2308@gmail.com

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohan-ghosh-2308

# **Summary**

A personable, dependable, and self-motivated Certified in Digital Marketing, certified SEO (Search Engine Optimization) & SEM (Search Engine Marketing) Expert, pursuing a dynamic role in Content & Digital Marketing &/or Data Analytics, to benefit the organization. Ability to work independently and as part of a team, with strong decision making and effective communication skills.

### **Skills**

Digital Marketing • SEO • SEM • Data Analytics • Data Management • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Operations Management • Marketing • Sales • Problem Solving • Network Administration • Project Management • Computer/Cisco Networking • Advanced Excel • Fitness

### **Experience**

**Marketing and Research Specialist (Remote),** Light House Tech LLC, India December 2021 – to present

- Use various network marketing platforms to promote client's website and increase the number of customer target groups and traffic to their websites.
- Play an effective role in planning implementation and strategic advancement.
- Work as a team and assist team lead to initiate and implement company's website marketing plan.
- Contribute to the company's R&D program.

**Computer Operator**, Maharishi Vidya Mandir Schools Group of India January 2020 – November 2021

- Develop marketing emails, make phone calls, and distribute correspondence, with concise and to the point messages simplifying complex topics.
- Create and maintain a variety of school-based records, lists, reports and account data from source documents.
- Maintain related accounts, including the collection of cash, issuing receipts and cheques, depositing funds, month end balancing, bank reconciliation and producing reports as required.
- Set up and track financial records, ledger book; verified and entered account transactions
  ensuring that actions are appropriate, properly coded and have the required supporting
  documentation.
- Provide information for review and approval by the Principal on employment related matters including monitoring and editing the weekly absence.
- Make Transfer Certificates with Principal's signature for students who are changing schools in India.

**Medical Billing Executive,** Porteck India Infoservices Private Limited, Noida, Uttar Pradesh 2018 - 2019

- Responsible for completing required paperwork to perform timely follow-up for insurance verification, patient pre-authorization, electronic referrals, timely medical billing and claims processing as well as claims submission and denial management
- Managed the resubmission of any claims that are not received by the insurance company or need to be corrected and resubmitted within allowable timeframes.

ROHAN GHOSH PAGE 1 OF 2

### **Education**

### Master Digital Marketing Certificate, LinkedIn Learning | March 2022

 As a Master in Digital Marketing I can help organizations connect with their customers by using social media in your marketing strategy. I have knowledge of how social media marketing and SEO work, know how to use the right tools and techniques, and have a good knowledge about best practices in this field.

### Digital Marketing: SEO Expert Certificate, LinkedIn Learning | February - March 2022

 As an SEO expert I can play a vital role in helping companies build their businesses and attract new customers through web traffic, analyze and optimize their site, and create an effective SEO strategy.

### Digital Marketing Specialist, LinkedIn Learning | March 2022

 I can now use my analytical and tactical skills to help grow and develop new opportunities for businesses, from marketing plans and content strategy to SEO and analytics. I am also able to promote products and services through various marketing channels like social media and email. In this course I got to practice with hands-on training in Google Analytics and Ads as well as Design marketing materials using the Adobe suite.

# **Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate**, Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere, Data Analysis | November 2021 - Present

 Learnt key analytical skills (data cleaning, data analysis, data visualization) and tools (spreadsheets, SQL, R programming, Tableau).

## Digital Marketing Certification: Semrush SEO Toolkit, Semrush Academy | February 2022

- Learnt how to analyze and optimize our site with in-depth SEO tools to grow visibility.
- Keyword research, site checks, traffic analytics, develop reports, and measuring success.

## Advanced Excel Training, BIZWIZ.CO.IN | June 2021

#### Digital Skills Certificate, Accenture | 2020

- Accenture's Digital Skills for Work & Life Certificate
- Accenture's Digital Skills: Artificial Intelligence Certificate
- Accenture's Digital Skills: Digital Marketing Certificate
- Accenture's Digital Skills: Mobile Certificate
- Accenture's Digital Skills: Social Media Certificate

### Bachelor of Science - BSc, Physics, CCS (Chaudhary Charan Singh) University | 2009 - 2012

• Specialized in Physics, Chemistry & Mathematics

# High School Diploma, Science, TRM Public School, Modinagar | 1995 - 2009

• Physics, Chemistry & Mathematics

### **Honors & Awards**

- 2014: 1st Position Delhi Police Running Race 1600m + Long Jump + High Jump
- 2014: 1st Position at Modinagar District Level Race 10km
- 2013: 1st Position Delhi Police Running Race 1600m + Long jump + High Jump
- 2011: 1st Position College Level 5km Race
- 2011: 1st Position in Para Military Force Race 5km + Long Jump + High Jump

ROHAN GHOSH PAGE 2 OF 2